Finding Aid for Center for the History of Medicine (University of Michigan) Oral History Interviews
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Center for the History of Medicine (University of Michigan) Oral History Interviews 2002-2007, 2011
University of Michigan. Center for the History of Medicine.
2 linear feet
05104 Bimu C502 2
Center was established as the Historical Center for the Health Sciences. records include interviews of emeritus University of Michigan Medical School faculty members conducted by the Center for the History of Medicine. Transcripts and audio recordings of interviews discussing their backgrounds, education, careers, and tenure at the University of Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Received from the Center for the History of Medicine (Donor No. 8111 ) in three accessions, in 2004, 2006, 2008, 2011 and 2012.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The interviews are open without restriction.
An oral history project undertaken by the University of Michigan Center for the History of Medicine, the project focused on interviewing retired or emeritus faculty members. Interviews were conducted form 202 to 2004.
An oral history project undertaken by the University of Michigan Center for the History of Medicine, the project focused on interviewing retired or emeritus faculty members in order to preserve their institutional knowledge of the Medical Center and the university.
Between the years 2002 and 2004, the center's assistant director for programs, Christine Bass, conducted four interviews. From 2004 to 2007, Enid Galler, proprietor of Voice Treasures, took over the interviewing process and conducted fourteen additional oral histories. All interviews include discussions of the faculty member's early life, education, and career accomplishments.
The interviews are recorded on audio cassettes or compact discs. In addition to these audio formats, there are one or more folders corresponding to each interview, which contain a typed transcript of the interview, a copy of the faculty member's curriculum vitae and in some cases, additional biographical information. The interviews conducted by Enid Galler include an index (with people, organizations, and subjects) and a detailed subject list. Mary Beth Reilly conducted later interviews.
Transcripts are arranged alphabetically by last name, with all audio materials in Box 2.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
University of Michigan. Center for the History of Medicine.; Medical sciences--Michigan.; Medicine.; University of Michigan. Medical School.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. Historical Center for the Health Sciences.
Contributors:
Abrams, G. D. (Gerald David), 1932-; Bartlett, Robert H.; Bohr, David F., 1915-; Bole, Giles G.; Bull, Frances E.; Christensen, A. Kent.; Davenport, Horace W. (Horace Willard), 1912-2005; Dean, George Arthur.; Fajans, Stefan S.; Gelehrter, Thomas D.; Henderson, John W. (John Woodworth), 1916-; Hubbard, William N.; Judge, Richard D.; Margolis, Philip M., 1925-; Morley, George W.; Neidhardt, Frederick C. (Frederick Carl), 1931-; Punch, Margaret R.; Sloan, Herbert, 1914-; Swain, Henry H.; Turcotte, Jeremiah G., 1933-
Genre Terms:
Oral histories.; CD-ROMs.; Sound recordings.
- Oral History Transcripts
  - Abrams, Gerald 2007 (Box 1)
  - Bartlett, Robert 2007 (Box 1)
  - Bole, Giles 2005 (Box 1)
  - Bohr, David F. 2003 (Box 1)
  - Bull, Frances 2005 (Box 1)
  - Christensen, A. Kent 2011, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Davenport, Horace W. 2002 (Box 1)
  - Dean, George 2007 (Box 1)
  - Dickinson, David 2005 (Box 1)
  - Fajans, Stefan 2005 (Box 1)
  - Gelehrter, Thomas D. 2012 (Box 1)
  - Henderson, John W. 2005 (Box 1)
  - Hubbard, William N. 2004 (Box 1)
  - Judge, Richard D. 2004 (Box 1)
  - Margolis, Philip 2006 (Box 1)
  - Morley, George W. 2002, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Neidhardt, Fred 2007 (Box 1)
  - Punch, Margaret R. 2004 (Box 1)
  - Sloan, Herbert 2006 (Box 1)
  - Swain, Henry 2005 (Box 2)
  - Turcotte, Jeremiah 2006 (Box 2)
- Oral History Audiocassettes
  (Transcripts in box 1)
  - Bohr, David F. 2003, 1 cassette (Box 2)
  - Davenport, Horace W. 2002, 7 cassettes (Box 2)
  - Morley, George W. 2002, 9 cassettes (Box 2)
  - Punch, Margaret R. 2004, 1 cassette (Box 2)
- Oral History Compact Discs
  - Bartlett, Robert 2007, 1 CDs (Box 2)
  - Bole, Giles G. 2005, 3 CDs (Box 2)
  - Bull, Frances 2005, 1 CD (Box 2)
  - Christensen, A. Kent 2011, 2 CDs (Box 2)
  - Dean, George 2007, 1 CD (Box 2)
  - Dickinson, David G. 2005, 2 CDs (Box 2)
  - Fajans, Stefan 2005, 3 CDs (Box 2)
  - Gelehrter, Thomas D. 2011, 2 CDs (Box 2)
  - Henderson, John W. 2005, 2 CDs (Box 2)
  - Hubbard, William N., 3 CDs (Box 2)
  - Judge, Richard D., 3 CDs (Box 2)
  - Margolis, Philip M. 2006, 2 CDs (Box 2)
  - Neidhardt, Fred, 200, 1 CD (Box 2)
  - Sloan, Herbert 2006, 1 CD (Box 2)
  - Swain, Henry H. 2005, 3 CDs (Box 2)
  - Turcotte, Jeremiah G. 2006, 1 CD (Box 2)